

■ maggied@mit.edu | ★ maggiedelano.com | maggiedelano | ● @maggied

# Summary\_

Maggie Delano is a PhD candidate working with Professor Charlie Sodini on a wearable fluid status monitor for patients with Congestive Heart Failure. She is interested in the interface of technology and medicine, particularly if/how technology can empower individuals and break down existing power structures. Maggie is a four-time Electrical Engineering Instructor for MIT's medical device design course, where she has mentored over 10 different clinical design projects. Maggie is also a meetup organizer and diversity advocate in the Quantified Self community and an avid self-tracker.

## **Education**

### **Massachusetts Institute of Technology**

PHD IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

Cambridge, MA, USA

Sept. 2012 - June 2017 (Expected)

### **Massachusetts Institute of Technology**

MASTER'S OF ENGINEERING IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

Cambridge, MA, USA

Aug. 2010 - June 2012

### **Massachusetts Institute of Technology**

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ELECTRICAL SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Cambridge, MA, USA

Sept. 2006 - June 2010

# **Experience**

#### Sodini Medical Electronics Research Group

Cambridge, MA, USA

PHD THESIS PROJECT

Sept. 2012 - June 2017 (Expected)

- Designing a wearable bioimpedance system to help reduce heart failure re-admission rates.
- Analog front end circuit design for bioimpedance measurements (1 kHz 1 MHz).
- Firmware development (MSP430).
- Electrode-skin interface characterization.
- Clinical testing in healthy participants (MIT) and hemodialysis patients (MGH).

**Fitbit** San Francisco, CA, USA

RESEARCH INTERN

June 2012 - August 2012

- Lead Prototype Electrical Engineer on the Fitbit Surge.
- Designed second generation PCB, including board level design, layout, and firmware (MSP430).
- Characterized system and made preliminary measurements in humans.

## **Sodini Medical Electronics Research Group**

Cambridge, MA, USA

Jan. 2010 - June 2012

- MENG THESIS PROJECT
- Designed a wearable cardiac monitor based around an MSP430 microcontroller.
- Records electrocardiogram and 3-axis acceleration data continuously for up to one week.
- Validated cardiac monitor in the Clinical Research Center at MIT.
- Performed as well or better than a commercial monitor, especially during running.

### **Boston Scientific (Cardiac Rhythm Management)**

St. Paul, MN, USA

June 2009 - August 2009

RESEARCH INTERN

- Developed and tested theories to characterize pacemaker lead heating in MRI.
- Wrote final report that became the basis for an FDA approval application.

# Publications and Talks \_\_\_

#### **PAPERS**

• Canning J, Helbert K, Iashin G, Matthews J, Yang J, **Delano M**, Sodini C, Zhang Q, "Noninvasive and Continuous Blood Pressure Measurement via Superficial Temporal Artery Tonometry," submitted to Engineering in Medicine and Biology

(EMBC) Conference, March, 2016.

- **Delano M**, and Sodini C, "A Long Term Wearable Electrocardiogram Measurement System," in *Body Sensor Networks* Conference, 2013; 1-6.
- Winokur E, **Delano M**, and Sodini C, "A Wearable Cardiac Monitor for Long-term Data Acquisition and Analysis," *Trans*actions on Biomedical Engineering, 2013 Jan; 60(1):189-92.
- Egner T, Delano M, and Hirsch J, "Separate conflict-specific cognitive control mechanisms in the human brain," Neuroimage 2007; 35(2), 940-948.

#### CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

- Delano M, "Building Myself Back Up." Show & Tell Talk, Quantified Self Global Conference, San Francisco, CA, June 18, 2015.
- Delano M, "ECG and Activity Tracking: What Can We Learn?" Show & Tell Talk, Quantified Self Global Conference, San Francisco, CA, October 10, 2013.

#### OTHER PRESENTATIONS

- Delano M, "Productivity and Quantified Self." Guest Lecture, STS.091 (Critical Issues in STS: Data as Self), October 21, 2013.
- Delano M, "A Long-Term Wearable ECG Measurement System." Center for Integrated Circuits and Systems (CICS) Review, Cambridge, MA, May 1, 2013.
- Delano M, "Motivation for the Quantified Self." Show & Tell Talk, Quantified Self Boston, Cambridge, MA, January 8, 2013.
- Winokur E, He D, **Delano M**, and Sodini C, "Clinical and Lab Measurements Using Wearable Medical Monitors." Center for Integrated Circuits and Systems (CICS) Review, Cambridge, MA, November 3, 2010.

#### **POSTERS**

- Delano M and Sodini C, "A Portable Bioimpedance Measurement System for Congestive Heart Failure (CHF) Management." Poster, IEEE Symposium on Medical Electronic Devices and Systems (ISMEDS), Cambridge, MA, May 8, 2014. Also presented at ISMEDS 2015 and MTL Annual Research Conference (MARC) 2015.
- Delano M and Sodini C, "A Long-Term Wearable Electrocardiogram Measurement System." Poster, Medical Electronic Device Realization Center (MEDRC) Workshop, Cambridge, MA, May 2, 2013. Also presented at MARC 2014.

# **Teaching**

## Design of Medical Devices (MIT 2.75/6.025)

**ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING INSTRUCTOR** 

- Four-time Electrical Engineering Instructor.
- Weekly one-on-one mentoring of 3-5 person student teams, each prototyping medical devices.
- Develop curriculum and syllabus.
- · Support student publications.
- Designed, wrote, and run yearly ECG lab.
- Designed, wrote, and graded problem sets.

## **Preparation for Undergraduate Thesis (MIT 6.UAT)**

• TA for two recitation sections working closely with faculty instructors.

• Ran recitations day-to-day.

- Provided individualized feedback to help students improve presentation skills.
- Filmed in class presentations.
- Graded assignments.

**TEACHING ASSISTANT** 

### Microcontroller Laboratory (MIT 6.115)

LABORATORY ASSISTANT

- Helped students during staffed lab hours.
- Ran lab checkoffs.
- Graded laboratory notebooks.

Cambridge, MA, USA

Sept. 2012 - Present

Cambridge, MA, USA

Fall 2010

Cambridge, MA, USA Spring 2010

# **Community Involvement**.

## MIT Senior House Cambridge, MA, USA

GRADUATE RESIDENCE TUTOR (GRT)

- Work as part of team of GRTs, faculty, and staff.
- Provide individualized and community support and resources for undergraduate students.
- Served on Housemaster Search Committee.
- Served on GRT Feedback Committee.
- Participated in GRT Role Meetings with Chancellor Barnhart.

### Quantified Self (QS)

Cambridge, MA, USA

Jan. 2013 - Present

Aug. 2014 - Present

MEETUP ORGANIZER

- Started a Boston based women's meetup group.
- Select show & tell speakers for Quantified Self Boston meetups.
- Wrote Quantified Self's first Code of Conduct.
- Served on Quantified Self's diversity committee for the 2015 Global Conference.

### **MIT Undergraduate Association (UA)**

Cambridge, MA, USA

Spring 2009 - Spring 2010

VICE PRESIDENT

- Elected in four ticket election with 50% of undergraduate vote (919/1806).
- Represented MIT undergraduates on issues ranging from student life to academic policy.
- Oversaw over 10 UA Committees.
- Ran UA's Institute Committee Nomination Process (Nomcomm).

## **Honors & Awards**

<b>Top Pitch in Session</b> , Microsystems Technology Lab Annual Research Conference	Bretton Woods, NH
<b>Top Pitch in Session,</b> Microsystems Technology Lab Annual Research Conference	Bretton Woods, NH
Analog Minority Scholarship, Texas Instruments	Dallas, TX
<b>Second Place in Category</b> , Intel International Science and Engineering Fair (ISEF)	Indianapolis, IN
<b>Top 6,</b> National Junior Sciences and Humanities Symposium (JSHS)	Albuquerque, NM
Semi-Finalist, Intel Science Talent Search (STS)	Washington, DC
	<b>Top Pitch in Session,</b> Microsystems Technology Lab Annual Research Conference <b>Analog Minority Scholarship,</b> Texas Instruments <b>Second Place in Category,</b> Intel International Science and Engineering Fair (ISEF) <b>Top 6,</b> National Junior Sciences and Humanities Symposium (JSHS)

# Selected Writing and Press\_

## WRITING

- **Delano M**, Using Inclusive Language in Research Articles. Medium, November 16 2015.
- Delano M, I tried tracking my period and it was even worse than I could have imagined. Medium, February 23, 2015.
- **Delano M**, "A Code of Conduct." Quantified Self Blog, June 27, 2014.
- **Delano M**, My Roommate Has An Iron Uterus. Period. The Zine., 2013.

#### **PRESS**

- "Ahead of What's Possible, Health Innovations Stem from Great Partnerships." MEDRC Research Feature, Analog.com, June, 2015.
- Eveleth R, "How Self-Tracking Apps Exclude Women." The Atlantic, December 15, 2014.
- Ramirez E, "Inclusion and Diversity at QS15." Quantified Self Blog, October 14, 2014.
- Dooe M. "Apps for Better Sleep, Apps to Keep you awake." WGBH Innovation Hub, April 11, 2014.
- Greenhall A, "Quantified Self at the Frontier of Feminism." Model View Culture Quarterly No. 1, 2014.

## Skills\_

**Hardware** Basic and Advanced Electronics Lab Skills (Soldering, Oscilloscopes, Impedance Analyzers, etc.) **PCB Layout** Altium, Eagle

**Software** Embedded C, Objective C (iOS), MATLAB, LaTeX, Python, Javascript, Version Control (Git, SVN)

**OS** Windows, Mac, Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, Fedora, RHEL)